翻译：野火春风 hongjie@gmail.com
－ 别在饭桌上看报.
－ 我正在看呢! 我还没看完!
￡- Don't read at the table.
￡- l'm reading that! l didn't finish!
不行!
No!
还有,别再玩弄你的头发了.
And stop playing
with your hair.
会让你的头发掉光的!
You're gonna make
it fall out!
你不用担心我的头发了
因为我就要把剩下的头发剃光了!
You can stop worrying about my hair
'cause l'm going to shave the rest off!
－ 什么?!
－ 没错, 我马上要剃光头了.
￡- What?!
￡- That's right, l'm shaving my head.
－ 哦,这也太傻了!
－ 这不是傻, 这是时尚.
￡- Oh that's asinine!
￡- lt's not asinine, it's hip.
－ 嗨, 我们家没有牛奶了.
－ 你自己倒吧.
￡- Hey, we're out of milk.
￡- Help yourself.
想听最新新闻吗?
你老爸想剃成光头了.
Want to hear the latest?
Your father wants to shave his head.
你怎么不试试把把脑袋伸到车窗外面呢？
Why don't you just stick your head
out the car window?
－ 我的剃须刀在哪里?
－ 行了, 坐下吧.
￡- Where's my razor?
￡- Oh sit down.
我们不可以在这家里剃头.
We do not shave
our heads in this house.
这是我的家
还有,这是我的头!
lt's my house
and my head!
你那副样子，我可不愿意和你在一起.
l'm not going to be seen
with you like that.
又抓住了个弱点了!
Another advantage!
我去把所有的剃须刀都藏起来.
l'm hiding
all the razors.
你不会剃头的.
You're not going
to shave your head.
当然不会.
Of course not.
我只是想看报纸.
l just want
to read the paper.
－ 嗨.
－ 怎么样?
￡- Hey.
￡- So?
－ 看了我写的东西了?
－ 那篇文章? 看了.
￡- Did you read my thing?
￡- The article? Yeah.
－ 好的, 好的, 好的. 等我一下.
－ 行.
￡- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Give me a second.
￡- Okay.
我的处女作还不错, 是吧?
Pretty good
for a first try, huh?
文章的观点如何?
看明白我要阐述的想法了吗?
What about the point of it?
See the point l was trying to make?
看到我正在煮的咖啡了吗? (与前句句式完全相同)
Do you see the coffee
l'm trying to make?
－ 行了, 去吧. 我马上就来.
－ 好的.
￡- Come on, go. l'll be right there.
￡- Okay. All right.
嗯, 最近怎样?
So, how are you?
其他人怎么样?
很高兴听听你的想法. 你怎么看的?!
How's everybody?
Glad to hear it. What do you think?!
行.
Okay.
啊...
Ah...
你就要喝咖啡了.
太有趣了!
You're drinking it now.
very funny!
你真有趣!
You are hilarious!
我有个多么让你开心的朋友啊!
What a funny friend
l have!
和我说说看吧!
Talk to me!
－ 我喜欢这篇文章.
－ 是吗?
￡- l like it.
￡- Yeah?
是的. 我只是－－ 认为有些很小，很小的问题.
Yeah. l just￡-￡- l have some minor,
minor things.
哦，老天, 我只能一辈子都作统计人员了.
Oh God, l'm gonna be
a stat guy for the rest of my life.
别这么说, 行不?
文章写得很好.
Stop it, all right?
lt's very good.
别这么说!
Don't say that!
什么? 你明白很好是什么意思么?
What? What do you think
very good means?
就是很糟糕!
very bad!
－ 你不是想听听我的意见?
－ 是的!
￡- Do you want my notes or not?
￡- Yes!
－ 那行.
－ 天哪!
￡- All right.
￡- Oh my God!
看看这些红色记号!
Look at all
the red marks!
真是一连串的打击啊!
This is a mob hit!
Andy, 如果你不是我的朋友,
Andy, if you weren't
my friend,
－ 我会说, "这文章很棒," 然后就走开.
－ 行啊, 你那样做啊!
￡- l'd say, "lt's great," and walk away.
￡- Yes, do that!
听好, 听好.
Listen, listen.
什么是男人和男孩的区别
What separates
the men from the boys
那就是是否能够听得进去别人的意见,
is the willingness
to take notes,
重写，让它变得更好.
rewrite and make
it better.
行吗?
Okay?
我把最重要的地方告诉你
(key to the mint,一匹非常出名的赛马).
l'm giving you the key
to the mint here.
好吧.
All right.
开始吧,
我能接受.
Go ahead,
l can take it.
我很想得到指点.
把关键得地方告诉我吧.
l want it.
Give me the key to the mint.
行啊.
你看, 就这里,
All right.
Look, right here,
这里有点重复了.
you get a little
repetitive.
哦! 哦!
Oh! Oh!
我明白了, 我明白了, 我明白了, 我明白了!
我明白了, 谢谢!
l get it, l get it, l get it, l get it!
l get it, thanks!
行,
现在看看这里－－
Okay,
now here￡-￡-
还有?!
There's more?!
－ 是的.
－ 我们能不能休息一下?
￡- Yeah.
￡- Can we take a break?
我才刚刚开始呢.
你不是很想听我的意见吗?
l'm just getting started.
Don't you want to hear this?
我只是需要休息一下.
l just need a moment.
－ Andy.
－ 我要休息一会儿!
￡- Andy.
￡- l said a moment!
－ 嗨, Deb, 我的牙刷放哪里去了?
－ 我把旧牙刷扔掉了.
￡- Hey, Deb, where's my toothbrush?
￡- l threw the old ones out.
今天我带孩子们去看牙医了，
然后买了一大把新牙刷.
l got a bunch of new ones when
l took the kids to the dentist today.
－ 那么那一把是我的?
－ 红的那把.
￡- So which one's mine?
￡- The red.
我不想要红的!
l don't want to be red!
那就拿蓝的吧.
Take the blue one.
蓝的那把是湿的.
The blue one is wet.
我刚刚用过.
l just used it.
恶心!
Ew!
你不知道, 我还用过放在那里的肥皂.
You know, l used
the soap in there too.
不会是我的肥皂吧?
Not my soap?
我都没有自己的卫生用品了.
l have no toiletries.
行了,
就这样吧?
Would you please,
all right?
今天在牙医那里，
我不得不应付我们的三个疯小孩.
l already had to deal with three
maniac kids at the dentist today.
最后，我都要用上奴佛卡因(一种局部麻醉剂)了.
By the end of it
l needed the Novocain.
别相信 Geoffrey.
Couldn't believe Geoffrey.
哎, 我今天一样过得很糟.
Yeah well, l had
a bad day too, okay?
我不得不和Andy讨论他的文章.
l had to talk to Andy
about his article.
哦，那文章一定很烂－－
Oh well, that must
have been awful￡-￡-
坐下来和一个成年人讨论. 哎呀!
sitting and talking
with an adult. Jeez!
－ Michael坐到了椅子上－－
－ 真糟糕.
￡- Michael gets into the chair￡-￡-
￡- lt was awful.
你不知道Andy多想成为作家.
You know how Andy wants
to be a writer.
－ 所以我要帮助他.
－ 我正要跟你说些事情呢.
￡- So l gotta help him.
￡- l'm trying to tell you something here.
行, 但是你不知道,
我读了他的作品
Okay, but you know,
l read his stuff
然后我得开始思考,
and then l got
to think about it,
然后我要对他的烂文章做些笔记.
and then l gotta make notes
on his stupid thing.
也许这取决于你的态度.
Maybe it was your attitude.
什么态度?
What attitude?
"他的烂文章"?
"His stupid thing"?
你不是把他的作品称为烂文章吗?
Did you call his article
a stupid thing?
没有对他这么说.
跟他说的时候, 我说文章写得很好.
Not to him.
To him, l said it was very good.
－ 我的老天.
－ 怎么了?
￡- Oh God.
￡- What?
很好? 嗯, 我明白你的很好是什么意思了.
very good? Hmm, yeah, l know
what very good means.
昨晚你对我做的炒菜是怎么评价的?
What'd you said
about my stir-fry last night?
我说很好啊.
That was very good.
－ 嗯－好.
－ 是啊.
￡- Mmm￡-good.
￡- Yeah.
很好的尝试.
我刚刚想说
Nice try.
l'm just saying
听到你的意见，可能对Andy来说非常重要,
it probably meant a lot
to Andy to get your feedback,
你可以对Andy更加友善一些.
and maybe you could have been
a little bit nicer.
哎, 当时你不在那里.
我可是很友好的.
Hey, you weren't there.
l was very nice.
我尝试给他指出文章的关键问题.
l tried to give him
the key to the mint.
关键问题?
The key to the mint?
你不会那么说吧,
是吧?
You didn't say that,
did you?
这只是一种表达方式而已.
lt's an expression.
哦, 那你就了解
Oh, and you are the keeper
了解所有的关键问题?
of the key to the mint?
不, 我－－
No, l￡-￡-
我恰好了解其中的一个关键问题而已.
l happen to have
one of the keys.
－ 听着, 我是很友好的.
－ 这就是你当时所用的语气?
￡- Listen, l was very nice.
￡- ls that the tone you used?
－ 没有什么语气不语气的.
－ 这肯定就是当时你的语气!
￡- There was no tone.
￡- There's tone right there!
对, 和你说话我的确用的这样的语气啊.
Yes, with you l'm having
tone right now.
行了吧?
Okay?
但是和Andy说话的时候， 我可是很友好的.
我很善解人意的.
But with Andy, l was very nice.
l was very understanding.
很有耐心.
然后他大喊大叫，让我很尴尬.
very patient.
And then he embarrasses me by crying.
你让他大叫了?!
You made him cry?!
－ Ray!
－ 他没有大叫，没有大叫.
￡- Ray!
￡- He wasn't crying crying.
他只是有点呼吸困难.
He was just kind of breathing hard
and shuttering.
－ 每个人都看着我们.
－ 哦, 真为你们遗憾
￡- Everybody's looking at us.
￡- Oh, l'm so sorry
你不得不坐到你的大喊大叫的朋友旁边.
you had to sit next
to your crying friend.
听着...
Listen...
看着别人痛苦，自己也很难受的
it's a lot harder to watch
the person in pain
要比那人更加难受.
than it is to be
the person in pain.
我在干活的时候，你也对我说过这话.
You said that to me
when l was in labor.
你那时在尖叫.
You were screaming.
你听我这么说了，
真让我吃惊.
l'm surprised
you heard that.
可怜的Andy.
Poor Andy.
你想想他为什么把他的文章给你看?
Why do you think
he gave you his article?
因为我是傻瓜啊.
Because l'm a sucker.
因为他敬仰你，尊重你
Because he looks up to you
and respects you
而且无论你说什么，他都会听的.
and whatever you say
to him he's going to listen to.
嗯, 但是当我和他说，别哭了，他并没有听我的啊.
Yeah, he didn't listen
when l told him to stop crying.
听着, 你在这一行已经非常成功了
Listen, you are
very successful
而他只是刚刚起步,
and he's just
starting out,
你一定要尝试改变你的态度
and you really have to try to go
out of your way
去鼓励他，要温和点d.
to be encouraging
to him and kind.
你要理解别人
You've got to understand
that other people
也有自己的感情.
have feelings too.
行啊!
All right!
现在我可以告诉你今天发生在我身上的事情了吗?
Now can l finish telling you
what happened to me today?
－ 今天你遇到什么事情了?
－ 看牙医的事情!
￡- What happened to you today?
￡- At the dentist!
嗯, 好的.
行, 行, 行, 说吧.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, go.
Michael做到了椅子上，
但是其他两个孩子争着想当第一个.
Michael gets in the chair
and the other two want to get in first.
这时他们就开始打架了，所以Gibbons医生
That's when the fighting
starts, so Dr. Gibbons
试着开动了噗噗玩具火车.
tries to turn on
the choo￡-choo train.
这时Geoffrey踢了医生一脚!
That's when Geoffrey
kicks him!
他们都开始尖叫－－
小孩们，医护人员-Gibbons医生.
They all start screaming￡-￡-
the kids and Dr. Gibbons, the hygienist.
－ 哦， 别这样.
－ 就是这样的.
￡- Oh no.
￡- That's right.
哦, 不会是这样的.
No, not that.
我下周正要去看牙医呢.
l have a dentist
appointment next week.
怎么了?
What?
我正在听呢!
l listened!
－ 嘿!
￡- Hey!
－ 我想和你谈谈文章的事情.
－ 好的.
￡- l want to talk about the article.
￡- Oh yeah, listen.
嗨, 上个星期我给你提出我的意见的时候,
Listen, last week
when l gave you the notes,
我想我可能没有切实考虑的你的...
l think maybe l wasn't
really thinking about your...
感情诸如此类的.
feelings or whatever.
不. 不. 不.
No. No. No.
我想谢谢你.
我没有很好地接受你的意见.
l wanted to thank you.
l didn't take it very well.
不, 不, 不,
你做得很好.
No, no, no,
you were fine.
还有，你的文章的确写得很好.
And your article's
really good.
我想告诉你应该坚持写下去
And l wanted to tell you
that you should stick with it
－ 我会尽我所能来帮助你.
－ 我有个好消息.
￡- and l'll help you however l can.
￡- Here's the good news.
你不用帮我了.
《体育画报》买下我的文章了!
You don't have to.
"Sports lllustrated" bought it!
什么?
What?
我给他们投稿了，
并且他们也录用了.
l sent it over there
and they bought it.
他们就要出版我的文章了!
你信不信?! 哈哈!
They're gonna print it!
Can you believe it?! Ha￡-ha!
哈!
Yah!
哇!
Wow!
所以我想－－ Debra认为我不会鼓励别人.
So l guess￡-￡- Debra thought
l wasn't being encouraging.
但是我想我所作的对别人还是有帮助的.
but l guess whatever l did
kind of helped.
当然, 当然.
Yes, yes.
在某种意义上, 是的.
ln a way, yes.
－ 什么意思?
－ 嗯...
￡- What do you mean?
￡- Well...
我并没有完全接受你的意见.
l didn't exactly
take your notes.
我的意思是, 我回家后开始思考这件事情.
l mean, l went home
and l thought about it.
我决定了，我喜欢我自己的写作方式，
然后我就投递出去了.
l decided l liked the way
l had it and l sent it.
哦.
Oh.
无法想象, 老兄.
lmagine that, man.
但是还是要谢谢你.
你的意见非常好!
But thanks anyway.
Your notes were very good!
所以你也就不再看报了?
So you're giving up
reading altogether?
我还可以看谷类食品包装盒啊(指看包装盒上面的广告).
l still have
cereal boxes.
除非Count Chocula突然降低它的标准
(Count Chocula是一种流行的早餐谷类食品).
Unless Count Chocula
suddenly lowers his standards.
你能告诉我发生什么事情了?
Do you want to tell me
what's going on here?
没什么. "体育画报"
以前办得很好, 现在成垃圾了.
Nothing. "Sports lllustrated"
used to be good, now it's bad.
他们现在已经没有可信度了,
也没有品位.
They have no credibility,
no taste.
哦, Ray. 是不是"体育画报"
又给你退稿了?
Oh, Ray. Did "Sports lllustrated"
reject you again?
没有.
No.
事实上是, 我为能被他们退稿而感到高兴,
As a matter of fact, l'm proud
of those rejections now,
因为这份报纸是业余级别的.
'cause that rag is
amateurville Jack.
他们发表了Andy的文章.
They're publishing
Andy's thing.
噢, 很棒啊!
Oh, that's great!
不, 不是这样的!
No, it's not!
但是Ray, 你应该感到高兴啊.
我的天哪!
But Ray, you should be happy.
Oh my gosh!
因为你帮助了他啊.
'Cause you helped him.
哦, 哦, 哦.
Oh, oh, oh.
他没有接受你的修改意见吧，是么?
He didn't take
your notes, did he?
Ray...
他怎么能没有理会你的关键要点，还能发表文章的?
how did he get into
the mint without your key?
他认识看门人(指审稿人员).
He knows the janitor.
你都不为他的成功感到高兴.
You can't even
enjoy his success.
我感到很高兴,
行了吧?
l'm enjoying it,
okay?
只是, 在那篇垃圾文章发表在 "体育画报"以后
Just, when that piece of crap
comes out in "Sports lllustrated,"
Andy会变得让人难以忍受.
Andy's gonna be
impossible.
因为他可能会认为自己已经是一个真正的作家了?
'Cause he might think
he's a real writer?
是的.
Yeah.
－ 他可能会变得自满自大.
－ 对的.
￡- And he might get full of himself.
￡- Right.
他会认为自己已经写得和你一样好了.
And he might think
he's as good as you.
－ 你不懂的.
－ 我懂啊.
￡- You don't understand.
￡- l understand.
今天是属于Andy的
而不是属于你的.
Today was all about Andy
and it wasn't about you.
－ 不, 不, 不, 不.
－ 是的.
￡- No, no, no, no.
￡- Yeah.
行了, 承认吧.
你有点以自我为中心了.
Come on, admit it.
You're a little self￡-centered.
以自我为中心?!
Self￡-centered?!
是的, 你所看到的
都是他的好消息对你的影响.
Yeah, all you can see
is how this news affects you.
我可以告诉你些事情吗?
你并不是只对Andy这样的.
And can l tell you something?
This isn't just with Andy.
－ 此话怎讲啊?
－ 就是我们说的lt's coming from those of us
￡- Where is this coming from?
￡- lt's coming from those of us
我们这些围绕着你转的人说的.
orbiting around you.
你认为
我以自我为中心?
You think
l'm self￡-centered?
我? 我? 我?
Me? Me? Me?
你知道我－－
我工作努力.
You know l￡-￡-
l work hard.
我努力来挣足够的钱来养活我们全家.
l try to make enough money
to feed this family.
我不得不忍受那些来咨询我建议的朋友们
l have to put up with friends
who ask my advice
然后他们又不听我提出的建议.
and then ignore
what l tell them.
－ 爸爸!
－ 我还得忍受拥塞的交通.
￡- Daddy!
￡- Then l put up with traffic.
－ 然后我还得回家...
－ 爸爸!
￡- Then l have to come home...
￡- Daddy!
...向妻子解释我自己
...and explain
myself to a wife
－ 因为她认为我是以自我中心的...
－ 爸爸!
￡- who thinks l'm self￡-centered...
￡- Daddy!
...这让我觉得－－
我听到了!
...which makes me think￡-￡-
l hear her!
怎么了, 宝贝?
What is it, honey?
我有1 ,000 美分了.
l have 1 ,000 pennies.
你没看到爸爸正在和妈妈说话吗, 小宝贝?
Did you see that Daddy
was talking, sweetie?
我以后再看你的硬币, 好吗?
And l would love to see
those pennies later, okay?
啊哈?!
Huh?!
不许看报.
No reading.
嘿, 嘿,你现在在干什么?
Hey, hey, what are you
doing there?
我正在切一块英国松饼.
l'm cutting
an English muffin.
不能切.
你该用叉子.
You don't cut it.
You use a fork.
你不会是用叉子来切东西吗.
You don't use a fork
to cut things.
－ 不是切, 是分割.
－ 什么?
￡- Not to cut, to split.
￡- What?
对的, 在那边的包装纸上就是这么说的. 看看吧.
Yeah, it says it right
on the wrapper there. Look at it.
用叉子分割.
叉子! 用叉子!
Fork split.
Fork! With a fork!
这只是说他们在工厂是用叉子来分割的.
All that means is they've split
it with a fork at the factory.
如果他们在工厂就用叉子分割的话
那么松饼就应该已经是被分割好的了的
lf they split it at the factory
it'd be open already
我也就没有必要对你说这些了!
and l wouldn't
have to talk to you!
你到底要不要吃这个?
You want this or not?
现在不吃. 看看你用餐刀干了些什么吧!
Not now. Look what you've done
with your knife!
你不仅把原来的裂缝弄坏了,
Not only have you killed
the crannies,
还把它们挤到了角落里!
you smooshed them
into the nooks!
真恨不得一巴掌把你扇到角落里.
l'm gonna smoosh you
into a nook.
－ 嘿.
－ 嗨, 亲爱的.
￡- Hey.
￡- Hi, dear.
－ 想来点英国松饼吗?
－ 别吃, 饼被切坏了!
￡- Want an English muffin?
￡- Don't do it, it's cut!
别说了!
Raymond,
Oh stop!
他们在包装盒上写着, 用叉子分割,
when they say on
the box, fork split,
这不就是说，他们已经帮你用叉子分割过了?
doesn't that mean they've started
it for you already?
比如说在工厂
用叉子分割?
Like in the factory
with a fork?
你有没有用过的牙刷吗?
Do you have any
unopened toothbrushes?
－ 当然有. 你要一只牙刷?
－ 是的, 我要－－
￡- Oh course. You need a toothbrush?
￡- Yeah, l need￡-￡-
－ 要蓝色, 对吗?
－ 对的.
￡- A blue medium, right?
￡- Right.
－ Robby!
－ 妈, Robby已经搬走了t.
￡- Robby!
￡- Ma, Robby moved out.
－ 什么事, 妈?
－ 他还是要来洗衣服的.
￡- What, Ma?
￡- He still has to do laundry.
Robby, 到橱柜
Robby, go
into the cabinet
去帮你哥哥拿个新的蓝色中等硬度的牙刷出来.
and take out a new blue medium
toothbrush for your brother.
蓝色中硬牙刷是我的.
我一直是用蓝色中硬牙刷的.
The blue mediums are mine.
l'm taking them with me.
Robby, 听我说, 帮你哥哥拿个蓝色中硬的牙刷出来
Robby, l said, get a blue medium
toothbrush for your brother
快点拿出来吧!
and bring it out
right now!
好吧!
All right!
我不会吃它了!
l am not eating that!
吃这该死的松饼吧.
Eat that damn muffin.
我是不是在不恰当的时间来找你了啊?
Am l catching you
at a bad time here?
没有, 亲爱的, 我们正在吃早饭.
No, dear, we're just
having breakfast.
给你吧.
Here you go.
这是黄色的.
That's yellow.
－ 哦.
－ 妈!
￡- Oh.
￡- Ma!
我说拿个蓝色的牙刷的, Robby!
l said a blue
toothbrush, Robby!
为什么一定要是蓝色的?
Why does it have
to be blue?
因为我就要蓝色的.
Because that's
what l wanted.
要是别人也想要呢，怎么办?
What about what
somebody else wants?
你有否为别人考虑过?
Do you ever think
about anyone else?
你是不是和Debra谈论过我?
Have you been talking
to Debra about me?
没有, 我和Debra讨论过Andy的事情.
No, l've been talking
to Debra about Andy.
我听说他的文章被
"体育画报"刊登了
l hear he got into
"Sports lllustrated."
哇!
那是国家级报纸.
Wow!
That's national.
哦, 是的,
爸爸.
Oh, yes, it is,
Daddy.
如果我说错了，你可以纠正我, Raymond,
Correct me
if l'm wrong, Raymond,
但是这不就是你一辈子的梦想么
but hasn't that been
a lifelong dream of yours
在"体育画报"上发表文章?
to get into
"Sports lllustrated"?
感觉如何啊?
How does it feel?
听着,我为Andy感到高兴, 行了吧?
Listen, l'm happy
for Andy, okay?
我并不是以自我为中心的.
l'm not self￡-centered.
什么? 什么?!
你们在笑什么?
What? What?!
What are you laughing at?
不以自我为中心?
嘿, 作为我的儿子，我爱你,
Not self￡-centered?
Hey, l love you like a son,
但是你是一只总想引起别人注意的猪.
but you always were a pig
for attention.
－ 一只总想引起别人注意的猪 ?
－ 是的, 甚至你还是婴儿的时候
￡- A pig for attention?
￡- Yeah, even as a baby
你会哭啊，哭啊，哭啊.
you would cry
and cry and cry.
看看我吧,
我肚子痛!
Look at me,
l got colic!
好了, 好了.
Yeah, yeah.
每次当你进来的时候，是什么情形?
Or how about every time
you walk in the door?
你知道,
每次都是有理由的.
You know,
there's always a reason.
"我结婚了."
"我有孩子了."
"l got married."
"l got kids."
"我有一只蓝色中硬毛的牙刷了."
"l gotta have a blue
medium toothbrush."
－ 你说错了.
－ 嗯.
￡- You're wrong.
￡- Yeah.
什么时候你进来只为打个招呼的?
When do you ever come over
just to say hello?
我的招呼是隐含的.
The hello is implied.
－ 妈, 你说我是你自我为中心的吗?
－ 你当然是啦, 亲爱的.
￡- Mom, am l self￡-centered?
￡- Of course you are, dear.
啊哈!
Aha!
但是你有权这样.
But you have every
right to be.
你是很特别的.
You're very special.
我们走吧.
都上船吧!
Here we go.
All aboard!
你既英俊,
又有魅力, 你还很成功.
You are handsome,
you are charming, you're successful.
你是优秀的父亲
还是英俊的儿子.
You're a marvelous father
and a beautiful son.
你很想知道，你是怎么变得以自我为中心的吧.
And you wonder how you
turned out self￡-centered.
你才是以自我为中心的.
You're the one
who's self￡-centered.
我辛辛苦苦弄这些松饼，你甚至都都不想吃它
l slave over those muffins and you
don't even have the decency to eat it
因为这些松饼的切片方法不正确!
because they're
not sliced right!
你又怎么样?
我要用你的方式来吃我的松饼 !
How about you?
l got to eat my muffin your way!
－ 我来吃松饼.
－ 别了, 你上楼去
￡- l'll eat the muffin.
￡- No, you go upstairs
给你哥哥去拿蓝色牙刷把.
蓝色牙刷并不都是给你买的!
and get your brother a blue toothbrush.
They're not all for you!
你在说什么啊?
现在我是以自我为中心了?
What are you saying?
l'm self￡-centered now?
你? 当然了!
You? Definitely!
"我不能在普通买衣服的地方买衣服!"
"l can't buy clothes
where normal people buy clothes!"
"我要我自己的公寓."
"每个人都攻击我!"
"l need my own apartment."
"Everyone shoots at me!"
－ 你才是以自我为中心呢!
－ 对，他是的.
￡- You're the one that's self￡-centered!
￡- Yes, he is.
－ 但是你也是的.
－ 谢谢. 嘿! 我现在明白了.
￡- But you are too.
￡- Thank you. Hey! l understand now.
用黄色牙刷，我也不会死.
l can live with yellow.
再见是暗示出来的!
The goodbye is implied!
嘿, "体育画报," 哈?
Hey, "Sports
lllustrated," huh?
别提那
"体育画报"了
Forget about
"Sports lllustrated."
他们把我的文章完全重写了.
They rewrote
my whole article.
－ 整篇文章?
－ 整篇文章.
￡- The whole thing?
￡- The whole thing.
但是他们刊载了.
所以他们肯定喜欢其中的某些东西.
But they bought it.
So they must have liked something.
很明显，他们喜欢是因为这篇文章是关于体育的.
Apparently they liked
that it was about sports.
他们只是不喜欢我所用的词语
They just didn't like
the words l picked
或者我文章的顺序.
or the order
l put them in.
的确有问题.
That stinks.
但是他们需要这篇文章，对吧?
你做的很好
But who needs them, right?
You did a good job
你应该继续保持
我会帮助你的.
and you should keep at it
and l'm here for you.
谢谢, Ray.
我应该听你的建议的.
Thanks, Ray.
l should have listened to you.
许多这样的家伙都和你有
A lot of what those guys
had problems with
一模一样的问题.
was exactly what you
had problems with.
是的－－ 哦，是吗?
Yeah￡-￡- oh yeah?
你是说体育画报的那些家伙们，是吗?
What, the "Sports
lllustrated" guys, yeah?
他们有同样的问题?
They had
the same problems?
是的， 但是－－
Yeah but￡-￡-
你给他们说过
我给你提过建议?
did you mention
that l gave you the notes?
－ 说了点.
－ 嗯, 他们知道我是谁, 是么?
￡- Kind of.
￡- Yeah, they know who l am, right?
我的意思是, 他们知道我是谁吗?
l mean, do they
know who l am?
也许, 我不知道.
Maybe, l don't know.
你提到我的时候，他们说了些什么?
What did they say when
you mentioned me?
我不确定, Ray.
我当时快哭了.
l'm not sure, Ray.
l was kind of crying.
哦.
真遗憾.
Oh yeah, yeah.
l'm sorry.
你提到我的时候，你没有哭吧?
You weren't crying when you
mentioned me, were you?
你究竟干了些什么?
What the hell
happened here?
用叉子分割.
Fork split.
翻译:野火春风    校对：野火春风
hongjie@gmail.com QQ:3234721